Marc Theodor Zaharescu

22 Bletchley Court, London, N1 7NX 07834634909 zaharescumarc10@gmail.com

I am a highly adaptable and motivated engineer with an inner drive for technology. Fully determined to expand my insight and practical experience which will lead to making a success of all career opportunities offered to me.

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham

First Class Honours in BSc Artificial Intelligence with Computer Science

2013-2017

"Gheorghe Lazar" National College

2009-2013

Romanian Baccalaureate Diploma 9,11/10 (A Levels Equivalent)

KEY SKILLS

ProgramingJava/Kotlin- advancedlanguagesJavaScript- advancedApex- advancedHaskell- intermediateOCaml- intermediate

Frameworks & Technical Skills

Node.js - advanced
React - advanced
SQL - advanced
Redux - intermediate
Dagger2 - intermediate
Terraform - intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

October 2017 - present

Software Engineer at TESCO

- Working in an agile and high profile web team, delivering critical functionality (login and registration) on top of an account management app
- Experienced with many modern web frameworks: Node.js, React and Redux.
- Worked for 3 months on the main groceries android app using: Kotlin, Java, Dagger2, Gradle.
- Part of the out-of-hours support team with the responsibility of troubleshooting and rectifying production problems.

October 2016 - May 2017

Lab Demonstrator

at The University of Birmingham

- Guiding students through the unit's content.
- Helping my fellow students with programming assignments, coaching them on different technical topics.
- Enabled me to consolidate previous year's knowledge.

September 2015 - September 2016

Data Analyst

at Talmix (formerly MBA & Co) November 2013 - December 2013

- Financial data modelling and analysis.
- Developed and customized the company's CRM (Salesforce).
- Developed Google Chrome Extensions to enhance several business processes.
- Helped me build upon my analytical and problem solving skills by working in an agile, proactive environment.

November 2014 - December 2014

Study Group Leader

for the Foundations of Computer - Science Module

- Learned to adapt to students' different academic levels, giving my mentees the opportunity to explore their own thoughts.
- Improved my ability to communicate with people openly.

VOLUNTARY WORK

January 2017 - February 2017 Asian Pacific Youth Exchange

- Worked on a climate action, UN project in Thailand.
- Developed strong presentation and analytical skills by designing a business plan for a self-sustaining social venture which aims to support a local community near Chaing Mai, Thailand.
- Led a team of international students from different learning backgrounds.

June 2016 - July 2016

Asia as the Global Future

- Gained international learning insight by following a politics and economics summer course hosted by the Hong-Kong University along with Perking University and Korea University.
- Made me build upon my critical thinking skills.

April 2015 - May 2015 **Study China Program**

- Lived and studied in China over a 3 weeks period.
- It was a challenging experience from both an academic and cultural perspective but I managed to adapt well right from the beginning.
- Helped me better understand cultural sensitivities, making me a more flexible, rounded person.

October 2014 - May 2015 Peer Assisted Study Sessions Leader

- Developed verbal and personal communication skills by speaking to large groups of students (12+ students).
- Showed originality by organising activities to verify student's understanding on the material presented.

ACADEMIC RECOGNITION AND AWARDS

- Winner of the 3rd Asian Pacific Youth Exchange Program
- Personal Skills Award (Modular, Activity)
- Asia as the Global Future Completion Award
- Study China Program Completion Award
- Sprach Diplom B2/C1

LANGUAGES AND INTERESTS

- Fluent in English and Romanian, German B2/C1, Level 3 Mandarin Chinese.
- My favourite recreation activities include playing field tennis, indoor climbing and socialising.

References

References available on request.